《诉讼双雄》前情提要
原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
我想让你多接些无偿案
I want to talk to you about doing more pro bonos.
如果你想接无偿案  你去接
If you want to take on a pro bono, knock yourself out.
一间律所的首席运营官
What is a COO of a law firm
首席翻译官
█ 网易见外
最该放弃的不就是无偿案吗
doing handing out pro bonos in the first place?
-我只是觉得...  -这是反问句  唐娜
- I just thought that it-- - Rhetorical question, Donna.
首席校对官
人人译视界
·
人人
我不在乎你怎么想
I don't care what you thought.
我需要你监督布莱恩·阿特曼
I need you to supervise Brian Altman.
-找别人管他  -该死  卡特里娜
- Have someone else manage him. - Damn it, Katrina.
翻译          小僵僵 辰星晓Reginamoon 木浅 arcadiachi 小溪1120 斗斗 行素
这是你成为资深合伙人的机会
This is your chance to be senior partner.
我只是想到了一周前的事
I was just thinking about where we were a week ago
那时我以为你是冷面无情的人
when I thought you were cold and heartless.
翻译          烟雨忆江南 silverlining 不見曦月 黑锤斯特 海云生 暴走小罐头 苏葵
这么快就从冷面无情变成了最好的朋友
And I went from that to being your best friend.
这么说也不太对
I wouldn't say best friend.
你想知道我的事
You want to know something about me?
校对          木浅
直接问我就好了
You go ahead and ask.
我怎么相信你说的是不是真的
And how should I trust that I'd get a straight answer?
因为我们现在是一条船上的人
Because I am on this team now.
我是把他的利益放在心上的
I've got its best interests at heart.
时间轴          张小满    Caroline
-我要离婚了  -你说什么
- I'm getting a divorce. - What?
我希望你能做我的律师
I was hoping that you could represent me.
后期          斯人
那是我弟弟  我还能怎么做
It's my brother; what am I supposed to do?
这有可能会让你惹上许多麻烦
I think that this could bring up a lot of shit for you.
他依然爱着你
He still loves you.
总监          木浅
你该再给他一个当父亲的机会
He deserves another chance as a father.
那是我做过的最不容易的事
It was one of the hardest things I've ever had to do.
我发誓我的心都少了一块  唐娜
I swear it took a piece of me, Donna.
┌
┐
└
┘
人人影视官方客户端
唯一下载渠道
app.YYeTs.com
┌
┐
└
┘
你可以认为
You could look at it
是你主动放弃了一块
like you chose to give a piece of yourself.
亚历克斯
Alex.
我能和你谈谈吗
Can I talk to you about something?
当然可以  唐娜  怎么了
Sure, Donna, what's going on?
自从我升职以来
Well, ever since I got promoted
我一直想找个办法回报社会
I've been looking for a way to give back.
然后我发现我有个朋友
And it turns out that a friend of mine
在为一个帮助受害女孩的慈善机构工作
is working for a charity that helps at-risk girls.
我想着于我而言最佳的贡献方式...
And I figured the best way for me to give some of my time--
就是说服一些律师去做贡献
Would be to convince some lawyers to give some of theirs.
没错
Exactly.
唐娜  我很想答应你  但我目前焦头烂额
Donna, I'd love to say yes, but I'm slammed right now.
而这种慈善机构
and a charity like this
理应得到的贡献比我能付出的要多
deserves more time than I can offer.
谢谢你听我说完
I appreciate you hearing me out.
我再去找找其他人
I'll find somebody else.
唐娜  我得问一句
Donna, I have to ask.
鉴于你上次接无偿案的结果
Given how it went the last time you took on a pro bono,
你这次有和罗伯特打过招呼吗
have you cleared this with Robert?
我不想看着你再被他骂一次
I'd hate to see him bite your head off a second time.
相信我  亚历克斯
Trust me, Alex,
同样的错误我不会犯第二次
I don't make the same mistake twice.
罗伯特对这事没意见
Robert's good with it.
那祝你找到能为你出力的人
Then I hope you find someone to handle it for you.
路易  我有什么能帮到你
Louis, what can I do for you?
不是我  我来是为了让你帮艾米特·福德
Not me. I'm here about what you can do for Emmet Ford.
你说的是世界上最火的在线零售的老板吗
You mean the owner of the hottest online retailer in the world.
没错  他想上市  但出了个问题
Yes I do. He wants to go public; there's a problem;
你得放下手头的所有事情
and you need to drop everything you're doing.
路易  我现在做不到
Louis, I can't right now.
我为瑞群森的案子忙得不可开交
I'm up to my eyeballs in the Ratchinson brief.
让其他人去做那个  这事太重要了
Then give it to someone else. This is too important.
如果真这么重要
Well, if it's so important,
你为什么不自己处理
why don't you handle it yourself?
我不能
I can't.
路易  怎么回事
Louis, what's going on?
卡特里娜  它能帮你成为高级合伙人
Katrina, you need this to make senior partner.
什么  我还以为我得通过向罗伯特展示
What? I thought I had to show Robert
我能管理员工来晋升  这我做到了
I could manage people to make senior partner, which I did.
不仅是罗伯特  每个合伙人都有一票
It's not Robert. Every partner gets a vote.
而保罗·该死的·波特想选...
And Paul goddamn Porter wants--
-别说我他想选那个王八蛋汉拉汉  -没错
- Don't tell me. That douchebag Hanrahan. - Yes.
卡特里娜  听着  我知道我让你失望了
Katrina, look, I know I let you down,
对此我很抱歉
and I'm sorry.
但只要你搞定这个案子
But you bring this home,
我保证你下个季度能成为高级合伙人
I promise you will be senior partner next quarter.
好吧  路易
Okay, Louis.
-我会处理好的  -很好
- I'll take care of it. - Good.
现在我得去传达几个更糟的消息了
Now I have to go deliver some more shitty news
那几个人可没有你这么通情达理
to someone who's gonna be less understanding than you.
我明白  你正在闹离婚
I get it. You're going through with the divorce,
但我不明白你为什么...
but I don't see why you can't--
不  我不接受  马库斯
No, I'm not okay with it, Marcus,
但我猜我不得不接受
but I guess I have to be.
听着  我得挂了  再见
Look, I got to go. Bye.
路易  不管什么事  不能等等吗
Louis, whatever it is, does it have to be now?
我也不想  哈维
I wish it didn't, Harvey,
我一周前接到了多米尼克·巴伦的的电话
but I got a call from Dominic Barone a week ago.
阿斯顿马丁提出收购麦肯诺汽车公司
Aston Martin put in offer to acquire McKernon Motors.
我猜你来是想问
And I assume you're here to ask
他们应该把这份提议扔到哪里  因为
where they should shove that offer because-
我来是想说多米尼克决定接受它
I'm here to tell you Dominic's taking it.
路易  如果麦肯诺被收购了
Louis, if McKernon is acquired--
多米尼克就不再是我们的委托人了
Dominic won't be our client anymore.
我知道
I know.
那就让他拒绝  没事  我自己打给他
Undo it. Never mind. I'll call him myself.
哈维  这就是他想要的
Harvey, it is what he wants.
胡说  他根本不知道自己想要什么
Bullshit, he doesn't know what he wants.
不  他知道
Yes, he does.
而且他现在是我的委托人
And he's my client now.
这件事已经决定了  我只希望你能接受
It's a done deal, and I need you to accept
他想要的  即使意味着我要失去他
what he wants, even if it means losing him.
路易  我一直在找你
Louis. I've been looking for you.
琼·沃尔什过来了
Joan Walsh is here.
等等  什么  她没跟我预约
Wait, what? She's not on my schedule.
我知道  她说是急事
I know. She says it's an emergency.
那抱歉我现在没空见她  唐娜
Well, I'm sorry I don't have time for her right now, Donna.
-为什么不见  -因为
- Why the hell not? - Because...
我另有安排了
I have an appointment on my other schedule.
什么叫另有安排
What's that supposed to mean?
就是说我现在要去见希拉  懂吗
It means I need to see Sheila right now, okay?
并且你也知道我是去干嘛的
And you know why.
让我理理  你现在要离开办公室
Let me get this straight. You're leaving the office
就算一位委托人有急事找你
when a client has an emergency
而你走就是因为想跟女朋友滚床单
so you can fool around with your girlfriend.
-哈维  -没错  就是这样
- Harvey. - Yes, I am.
我知道现在不合适提这个要求
And I know this isn't the best time to ask,
但她本来就是你的老客户了
but she is an old client of yours.
所以如果能请你替我去见她
So if you can please take the meeting,
不管什么事  回来之后都由我来解决
I will handle whatever it is when I get back.
那好  路易  你就出去然后享受
Sure, Louis, you go ahead and enjoy
你悠闲的午后时光吧
your afternoon delight.
我就呆在这里让多米尼克卖掉自己的公司
I'll just be here letting Dominic sell his company
顺便在你不在的时候给琼·沃尔什当保姆
and babysitting Joan Walsh while you're gone.
哈维  你来干什么  我还在
Harvey. What are you doing here? I was--
等路易过来
Expecting Louis?
他现在没空
Well, he's not available right now,
而我听说你有急事  琼
but I hear you have an emergency, Joan.
不妨你就直接告诉我
So why don't you read me in.
一位叫黛西·琼斯的模特发布了一段视频
A model named Daisy Jones posted a video claiming
她声称我们公司的遮瑕膏让她过敏了
my concealer gave her an allergic reaction.
因此我们新产品的销售额正在下降
Sales on my new line are tanking.
好的  我会处理
All right, I'll take care of it.
她主要在哪里活动  纽约还是迈阿密
Where is she based? New York or Miami?
-克利夫兰  -你说什么
- Cleveland. - I'm sorry?
她不是你指的那种典型模特  哈维
She's not your typical model, Harvey.
她是个网红
She's a digital influencer.
好吧  那她的经纪人是谁
All right, well, who is she managed by?
她妈妈  至少就我所知如此
Her mother, last I checked.
琼  她多大了
Joan, how old is this person?
16岁
16.
那恕我直言
Then, with all due respect,
用一个礼品篮把她打发走就行了
send her a gift basket and be done with it.
哈维  你不明白
Harvey, you don't get it.
这个姑娘有五千万粉丝
This girl has 50 million followers.
我们需要起诉她
We need to sue her into the ground
在她搞垮我整个公司之前
before she tanks my whole company.
但我们也需要保护好你的形象
We also need to be conscious of your image,
起诉一个16岁小姑娘画面可不好看
and suing a 16-year-old isn't a pretty picture.
我不担心什么画面好不好看  哈维
It's not the picture I'm worried about, Harvey.
那个视频才是最关键的
It's that video.
所以是你找到办法把事情解决
So are you going to find a way to get it down,
还是我要另请高明了
or do I need to find another firm who can?
*看到钱  就愿意留下吃饭*
* See the money, wanna stay for your meal *
*给你太太再拿块馅饼*
* Get another piece of pie for your wife *
*所有人都想知道那感觉*
* Everybody wanna know how it feel *
*所有人都想见见那景象*
* Everybody wanna see what it's like *
*豆子馅饼我也愿吃  我不在乎*
* I'll even eat a bean pie, I don't mind *
*我和妹子忙着赚钱*
* Me and Missy is so busy, busy making money *
*好了*
* All right *
*退开点  我要跳舞*
* All step back, I'm 'bout to dance *
诉讼双雄  第八季  第六集
*美钞爵士摇摇摇*
* The greenback boogie *
早上好  唐娜
Good morning, Donna.
萨曼莎
Samantha.
今天我有什么可以帮你的吗
What can I do for you today?
实际上  我觉得我可以帮你一些忙
Actually, I thought there might be something I can do for you.
我听说你正在为你的无偿服务案找代理人
I heard you're looking for representation for your charity.
谢谢你主动帮忙
Oh, that's nice of you to offer,
但我知道罗伯特有多倚重你
but I know how much Robert leans on you,
我觉得他不会同意
and I don't think he's gonna be okay
你替我做事的
with me doing it if it means you doing it.
为什么我感觉
Why do I get the feeling
即使他同意了  你也不愿意
that even if he would be okay with me doing this you aren't?
好吧  你想听实话吗
Okay. Do you want the truth?
我觉得你不适合接这个案子
I don't think you're the person for this.
因为你还不信任我
Because you still don't trust me.
因为你没有表现得让我能信任你
Because you haven't shown me I can.
好吧  随你怎么想
Okay, have it your way.
我觉得亚历克斯肯定会表现得非常出色
I'm sure Alex will knock it out of the park.
等等  他太忙了
Oh wait, he's too busy.
你可以找一个初级合伙人接这个案子
You could always try one of those junior partners.
当然  他们都非常害怕罗伯特
Of course, they're all too afraid of Robert
不敢在公益诉讼案上浪费时间
to spend billable hours on a pro bono.
-说完了吗  -我不知道  我该闭嘴了吗
- Are you done? - I don't know. Am I?
先告诉我你为什么这么想接这个案子
Not until you tell me why you want this so much.
如果我告诉你是因为我热爱慈善
Well, if I told you it's because I care about the work
你是不会相信的
this charity does you'd never believe me.
所以不如就说
So why don't we just say
是一只小鸟让我这么做的
it's because a little birdie asked me to.
好吧  萨曼莎
Okay, Samantha.
我会把他们的文件发给你
I'll send you their files.
布莱恩  你在这
Brian, there you are.
我需要你帮忙
I need your help with something.
当然可以  什么事
Sure, what is it?
艾米特·福德的公司
Emmet Ford hit a roadblock
在股交所上市时遇到了一些困难
getting listed on the stock exchange
我们需要帮他扫清障碍
and we need to blow that roadblock away.
卡特里娜  不管是什么障碍
Whoa, whoa, Katrina, whatever this is,
你自己都能搞定
you can handle this yourself.
你为什么要来找我帮忙
Why are you coming to me with it?
有三个原因
Three reasons.
第一  你有更多处理股票交易案件的经验
One, you have more stock exchange experience than I do.
-第二  我想硬气一点  -第三呢
- Two, I want a show of force. - And three?
唐娜曾经说过
Let's just say Donna once said that
你能让身边的人变得更好
you make everyone around you better.
我处理这个案子时需要保持最佳状态
And I need to be at my best on this case.
-那我同意了  -快看资料
- Then I accept. - Then read up.
我们一个小时以后见客户
We're meeting them in an hour.
唐娜  我正好要找你
Donna, just the person I was about to come see.
-是吗  -你好像很不安
- Oh, is that a fact? - You seem perturbed.
的确  因为萨曼莎刚刚
I am. Because Samantha just asked
要接我的公益诉讼案
to represent my charity and there's no way
要不是她从你这知道的消息
she would have done that if she hadn't
她肯定不会提出这种要求
heard about it from you.
唐娜  你们对彼此的第一印象不好
Donna, you two got off on the wrong foot,
我知道她想改善你们的关系
and I know for a fact she wants to fix it.
你怎么会知道
And how do you know that?
因为当我带着这个案子去找她时
Because when I came to her with this
她说接这个案子可以一石二鸟
She said it'll kill two birds with one stone,
其中一个目的就是向你示好
and one of those birds was making good with you.
我还是希望你从来没去找过她
Well, I still wish you hadn't gone to her at all.
这意味着我应该撕了这张支票吗
Does that mean I should tear up this check?
这可是500万美元的捐赠
This is a donation for $5 million.
萨曼莎在接你的公益案之前
That Samantha insisted I get
坚持要给我的
before she took on your charity.
唐娜  她是认真的
Donna, she's serious about this.
好吧  亚历克斯  我给她个机会
Okay, Alex, I'll give her a chance.
谢谢你给我这张支票
Thank you for this check.
福德先生  我是卡特里娜·班尼特
Mr. Ford, I'm Katrina Bennett.
-这是布莱恩·阿特曼  -很高兴认识你们
- This is Brian Altman. - It's nice to meet you both.
我们已经看过你的资料
We've read up on your situation,
但我们还想听你亲自说下情况
but we want to hear it directly from you.
好的  我来说
Okay, here it is.
我在过去六个月里
I've spent the last six months
一直在为我们的公司上市造势
trying to drum up interest in our IPO.
到了最后关头
And then at the eleventh hour,
股交所突然不再支持我
the stock exchange pulls a rug out from under me.
-他们为什么这么做  -你去问马克·艾肯
- Why would they do that? - Ask Marc Aiken.
董事会主席
The Chairman of the board?
对
Yeah.
那个混蛋从我们在高盛
The jackass has had it in for me
工作的时候就跟我针锋相对
ever since we worked together at Goldman.
董事会说他们不再支持我
The board said they pulled support
是因为对我们网站的内容有疑虑
because of concern over our site's content,
但我非常清楚
but I know damn well--
这只是马克想要整你的借口
It's just a pretext for Marc to screw you over.
没错
Exactly.
如果得不到注资
If I don't get this infusion of capital,
我就寸步难行
I am dead in the water.
那我们需要做的就是
Then all we need to do
证明这是恶意谋害  就没问题了
is show this is bad faith and you're in.
应该不是很困难
And that shouldn't be too hard.
我们只需要拿到董事会会议记录
All we need are those board minutes.
我已经试过了  纪录被封起来了
I tried that myself already; they're sealed.
-那我们就把纪录解封  -怎么解
- Then we need to unseal them. - How?
让马克·艾肯对你恨之入骨这事记录在案
By getting it on record that Marc Aiken hates your guts.
我知道我们会面是因为几颗黑头的原因
All right, I understand we're here because of a few blackheads.
把视频从网上删除需要什么条件
So what's it gonna take to get that video down?
我的客户是靠脸吃饭的  斯佩克特先生
My client's complexion is her livelihood, Mr. Specter.
这次意外不仅损害了她的名声
Not only did this incident harm her brand,
还给她带来了情感上的痛苦
it brought her emotional anguish.
太糟糕了  我一个礼拜都无法上传视频
It was so bad I couldn't post a video for a week.
除了中伤我客户的那一段
Except the one defaming my client.
我得让观众知道这事对我的脸造成的后果
Well, I had to show people what it did to my face.
我感觉很丢人
It was shaming.
这就是为什么除了视频不能删之外
Which is why in addition to the video staying up
我们还准备了这个
we've prepared this.
听我说
Listen to me,
如果每次一个16岁女孩
if every 16-year-old girl filed suit every time
照镜子时觉得自己不够美就去起诉
she wasn't happy with what she saw in the mirror,
我国的司法系统会瘫痪的
our legal system would grind to a halt.
我可不是普通的16岁女孩  斯佩克特先生
I'm not every 16-year-old girl, Mr. Specter.
你想让我把视频删除并且放弃上诉吗
And you want me to take down that video and not file this?
-我要一千万美元  -我明白了
- I want $10 million. - I see.
-这是在敲诈  -这是合理索赔
- So this is a shakedown? - This is a legitimate claim,
而你最明智的做法就是签支票付钱
and your wisest course of action would be to write that check.
我的做法将是对你提出诽谤上诉
My course of action is gonna be to hit you with a defamation suit
因为你根本没有证据
because you have no proof
是我们的产品导致了你的皮肤问题
our product caused your break outs.
我觉得你不知道我有五千万名粉丝
And I don't think you understand that I have 50 million followers
我说什么他们做什么
who will do anything I tell them to.
所以即使视频被删除了
So even if that video comes down,
我也能告诉他们不用你客户的产品
I can tell them not to use your client anyway.
够了  我不关你多大
That's it. I don't care how old you are.
你知道自己在干什么
You know what you're doing.
这些后果都是你自找的
You deserve what's coming for you,
还有这次会面结束了
and this meeting's over.
-好的  哈维  -什么好的
- Okay, Harvey. - Okay, what?
好的  为何你不开几个
Okay. Why don't you make your jokes
关于我和希拉造人的玩笑
about me and Sheila procreating
然后给我详细讲讲琼的意外事件
so we can get to you filling me in on Joan's emergency.
我不需要给你讲  路易  我来做就行
I don't need to fill you in, Louis. I got it from here.
不行  你什么资料都没有
No, you don't have anything.
你只需要临时照看她一下
You were just supposed to babysit her.
这就是真正在工作的关键  路易
That's the thing about actually being at work, Louis.
情况随时变化  你也得随着调整
Situations change and you make adjustments.
这不是什么情况  这是你把我客户抢了
This isn't a situation. This is you taking my client.
当时是你同意客户如果愿意的话
And you were the one okay with clients leaving
随时可以离开
if that's what they wanted.
所以是这个原因
So that's what this is about.
你生气是因为我当时让多米尼克
Your mad because I let Dominic do
去做正确的选择
what was best for him.
不  是因为你离开办公室
No, this is about you left the office
去跟你女朋友造人
to get your girlfriend knocked up.
我接了案子  就要把这案子做完
I started working a case, and I'm gonna finish it.
你别把希拉卷进来
Don't you bring Sheila into this.
不是我  路易  是你把她卷进来的
I didn't, Louis. You did.
现在你给我好好听着
Now, you listen to me closely
我不说第二遍
'cause I'm not gonna say this again.
这个案子不需要你的参与了
Your services are no longer needed on this case.
艾肯先生  你对艾米特·福德的感觉如何
Mr. Aiken, exactly how do you feel about Emmet Ford?
-有好有坏  -有好有坏
- Ambivalent. - Ambivalent?
你们一起工作了七年
You worked together for seven years.
问过也回答过了  你们到底想说什么
Asked and answered. Where is this going?
想说你的客户蓄意破坏
It's going to the fact that your client
艾米特·福德的公司上市
deliberately tried to sabotage Emmet Ford's IPO
就因为他不喜欢艾米特
because he doesn't like him.
纯属胡扯
That's bullshit.
-是吗  那你为什么打了他 -什么
- Really, then why did you punch him? - What?
如果你喜欢某人  为什么你会打他
Why would you throw a punch at someone if you like them?
我没说我喜欢他  而那起意外
I didn't say I like him, and that incident
是高盛交易大厅发生的
happened on the trading floor at Goldman.
在那里互相打两拳是友好的表现
Throwing punches was considered friendly.
我得告诉你  马克  听起来可不友好
I got to tell you, Marc, it doesn't sound friendly.
我不在乎听起来什么样
I don't care what it sounds like.
那我告诉你看起来什么样
Then let me tell you how it looks.
你们打了架  你心怀积怨
You had a fight; you held a grudge;
当你有机会能报复你讨厌的人时
and when you got the chance to screw over
你定会抓住机会
a man you hate, you took it.
我没有报复他
I didn't screw him over.
但你确实讨厌他  对不对
But you do hate him, don't you?
好吧  你知道吗  我受不了他
Okay, you know what? I can't stand him.
我觉得他就是个装模作样的贱人
I think he's a sanctimonious son of a bitch
别说再也不用见他  认识他我都后悔
and if I never see him again, it'll be too soon,
但我没有阻挠他的交易
but I did not keep him off that exchange.
如果你仍不打算告诉我们实话
Then if you're not going to tell us the truth about that,
董事会会议记录也会证明
the board minutes will.
你们无权查阅会议记录
You have no right to those minutes.
不  我们有  既然他承认存在个人偏见
We do, now that he's admitted personal bias.
那要么就是我们申请查阅会议记录的传票
So either we can subpoena those minutes
并在庭审时公开播放录音
and show this tape in open court,
要么就是你今天就交出来
or you can turn them over today.
不过你最好快点做决定
But you better decide fast
因为传票我已经起草好了
because I've already drafted that subpoena.
今晚会给你们
You'll have them by the end of the day.
然后我说  这不一样
And then I said, "It's not the same."
然后他说  反正无所谓
And then he said, "Well, you're the one
客户流失的人是你
who's okay with clients leaving."
然后他就提起希拉  然后我就很恼火
And then he brought up Sheila, and then I got really mad,
然后很伤心  然后就打电话给了你
and then I got really sad and called you.
现在怎么办
Now fix it.
路易  通常你和哈维的矛盾
Louis, customarily I find your frustrations
都完全是你自己造成的
with Harvey to be entirely of your own making,
但是这一次
but in this instance,
听上去错的像是哈维
it sounds like Harvey may be the one in the wrong.
我的老天  那我真得
Holy shit, I need to go out
马上出门买张乐透彩了
and buy a lotto ticket right now.
路易  听我说
Louis, stay with me.
你们两个已经彼此相熟很久了
You two have known each other a long time.
你们经历了许多波折起伏
You've had your ups and downs.
没错  我感觉我们俩几乎像情侣似的
Yeah, I know, it's like we're almost in a relationship.
不是几乎  就是
Not almost, it is a relationship.
我的天
Oh, my God.
我居然在跟哈维搞对象
I'm in a relationship with Harvey.
我能当攻吗
Can I be the boy?
哦不忘了它  我才不在乎
Oh, scratch that, I don't even give a shit.
我居然跟哈维在一起了
I'm in a relationship with Harvey.
你是想挽救这段关系
And would you like to work on that relationship?
还是想接下来的时间都用来
Or spend the rest of the session
庆祝它存在的事实
celebrating its existence.
我想我们都知道答案
I think we both know the answer to that,
但是我决定继续
but I'll settle for working on it.
既然如此
In that case...
如果你问哈维
what would Harvey say
他为什么那么生气  他会怎么说
if you were to ask him why he is so upset?
我不知道  他可是哈维
I don't know. He's Harvey.
他估计会说  我不管我全对  都是你的错
He'd say, "I'm right. You're wrong."
-轻抚秀发而后扬长而去  -路易
- Touch his hair and leave. - Louis.
如果你不能把他当成一个普通人的话
If you cannot see him as human being,
那我也帮不了你
I cannot help you.
-如果我带他来呢  -什么
- What if I brought him in? - Excuse me?
你也做夫妻关系咨询的
You do couple's counseling.
如果我带他一起来解决我们的关系问题呢
What if I brought him in to work on our relationship?
那不是我刚刚想说的意思
That is not exactly what I meant...
-你刚刚说我们是一对  -我没那么说
- You just said we're a couple. - I didn't say that.
那你说什么了
Well, then what did you say?
因为我不知道他会怎么想
Because I don't know what he's feeling,
但我只知道我们需要帮助
but I do know that we need help.
好吧  路易
Okay, Louis.
如果你能带他来  我会帮你们
If you can bring him in, I'll help.
你看完会议记录了吗
Did you finish reading the minutes?
嗯  我看了两遍
Yes. I read them twice
以确保没有漏掉任何有用的信息
to make sure I wasn't missing anything.
没有漏的
Well, you didn't.
所有内容都在讲艾肯如何试图
All these show is hours of Aiken lobbying
游说维持艾米特的公司
to keep Emmet's business
以及所有人都在如何反对他
and everyone else lobbying against him.
我知道  他在耍我们
I know. He set us up.
所以我们在首次公开募股倒计时的日子里
So we'd spend half the day wasting our time
浪费了半天的时间
while the clock on that IPO is ticking.
我得整晚留在这了  因为
Now I have to stay here all night because
我们快没时间了  而我不能输掉这个案子
we're running out of time, and I'm not losing this case.
那我只有一个问题
Then I just have one question.
印度菜还是中国菜
Indian or Chinese?
因为如果你要加班  我也留下
Because if you're staying here all night, I am too.
印度菜吧
Indian.
谢谢你  布莱恩
Thanks, Brian.
你可真美啊
Don't you look nice.
现在一天刚过半就要玩大变身了吗
We doing costume changes in the middle of the day now?
首先  现在不是中午
Okay, first of all, it is not the middle of the day,
其次  我要参加你说的那个慈善晚宴
and, second, I'm going to a gala for the charity
你之前说自己没时间去的
that you said you didn't have time for.
要是我早知道你穿的这么美
Well, if I'd known you were gonna dress like that,
怎么也得挤出时间去
I'd have made time.
要是我早知道
And if had known that
一个已婚男士要在工作时间勾搭我
a married man was going to hit on me at work,
我会丢给他一堆文书去处理
I would have served him with papers.
别嘛  宝贝儿  别这么凶
Come on, baby, don't be like that.
说真的  唐娜  我很高兴萨曼莎的事结了
Seriously, Donna, I'm glad it worked out with Samantha.
谢谢  亚历克斯
Thanks, Alex.
我也很高兴
I'm glad it did too.
布莱恩  不知道你是怎么找到这个餐厅的
Brian, I don't know where you found this place,
但这是我大学以来吃过最棒的咖喱了
but this is the best masala I've had since college.
我才意识到
I just realized this is, like,
这已经是我们一起吃的第三顿晚餐
our third dinner we've had together,
但我竟然不知道你上的哪所大学
and I don't even know where you went to college.
你如果非得知道的话  我上的普林斯顿
Well, if you must know, I went to Princeton,
但在你问我的专业之前  我不能
but before you can ask about my major, I couldn't dec--
我了个去  普林斯顿
Holy shit, Princeton.
布莱恩  这没什么大不了的
Brian, it's not that big a deal.
这里每个人都上的哈佛法...
Everybody here went to Harvard Law--
我的重点不在这
I'm not talking about that.
-我说的是托尼·高德  -谁是托尼·高德
- I'm talking about Tony Gold. - Who's Tony Gold?
我高中辩论队里的死对头
He was my rival on the debate team in high school.
他知道我梦想的大学是普林斯顿
He knew Princeton was my dream
而我的父母又负担不起送我
and that my parents couldn't afford to send me
去参加面试
to the interview in person.
所以托尼主动提出让我搭便车
So Tony offered to let me ride up
和他的家人一起  作为和谈
with his family as an olive branch.
-面试如何  -他放了我鸽子
- How'd the interview go? - He never picked me up.
普林斯顿大学那边以为我临阵脱逃
Princeton thought I'd bailed;
他进了  我没有
he got in; I didn't.
布莱恩  这太过分了
Brian, that's horrible.
的确  但是托尼编了一个扯淡的理由
It is, but Tony came up with a bullshit story
解释了他的缺席  我竟然还信了
about why they never showed, and I believed him.
直到他弟弟告诉我事实真相
Until his little brother told me the truth
那都是好几个月后了
a few months later.
你想说什么
What are you saying?
我想说的是托尼没办法把这事憋在心里
I'm saying Tony couldn't keep it to himself.
因为当你做了这种事情
Because when you do something like that--
你一定想说出来
You have to tell someone.
也就是说我们只需要找到
Which means all we need to do is find
马克·艾肯的弟弟
Marc Aiken's little brother.
你把咖喱沾到你
You got a little masala on your...
另一边
Other side.
你的  来
Your--here.
我帮你擦
Let me get it.
怎么
What?
我搞得更糟糕了
I just made it 1,000 times worse.
你看上去就像麦当劳叔叔
You look like Ronald McDonald.
我以为你天天给儿子擦嘴呢
I thought you do this with your son, like, every day.
其实我已经好几个月没这么做了
Well, I haven't had to do it with him in months
因为他已经把食物当作小火车
because his food is the train,
稳稳当当地送进嘴巴这个车站里了
and he keeps it in the station.
-把纸巾给我  -不给
- Ha ha, give me that napkin. - No.
先等我拍张照
Not till after I take a picture.
不准你拍
No, you are not taking a picture of me.
你怎么早先没想到这个
Well, maybe you should have thought of that
在我把酱抹你一脸之前
before you let me wipe sauce all over your face.
好啦  我给你擦了
All right, I'll get it off.
我们还是不要再吃咖喱了
I don't think we should eat anymore masala.
唐娜  对于你的捐款我真是感激不尽
Donna, I cannot thank you enough for your donation.
你已经作出了这么大的贡献
You're already making such a difference.
别说了  佩吉  你才是那个
Oh, please, Peggy, you're the ones
作出真正贡献的人
making the real difference.
我只是很高兴能够帮上忙
I'm just happy I could help you do it.
抱歉  我离开一会儿
Will you excuse me for a minute?
去吧
Sure.
-萨曼莎  -唐娜
- Samantha. - Donna.
在这儿看到你真是意料之外
I have to say I didn't expect to see you here.
我自己也觉得很意外
I didn't expect to be here.
你是来向我展示你的摇曳身姿的么
Did you come to show me how good you look all dressed up?
如果我说我就是为了见你才来的呢
What if I came to see how good you look all dressed up?
惠勒女士  你在勾搭我么
Miss Wheeler, are you flirting with me?
我要说是  你会做何感想
And how would that make you feel if I was?
你在搞笑吧  我可是去过戏剧训练营的人
Are you kidding? I went to theater camp.
我还是很想知道你在这的原因
But I would still like to know why you're here.
在我的印象里你是那种
I mean, you don't strike me as the kind of person
除非万不得已不会出现在这种场合的人
who would come to an event like this unless she had to.
没错  但如果我要帮这些人打官司
I wouldn't, but if I'm gonna represent these people,
我得知道他们做什么  怎么做的
I need to know what they do and how they do it.
既然我们都谈到了工作
While we're on the subject of working,
我拿到了亚历克斯的那张支票
I got that check from Alex.
你是说你同意我这么做吗
Is that your way of saying you're good with me doing this?
没错  但不只是因为钱
It is, but it's not just because of the money.
你出现在这里  表现出了你的兴趣
You're here showing interest.
证明你正是这地方需要的代表人
That's just the kind of representation this place needs.
既然如此  或许我们应该先对食物下手
Well, in that case, maybe we should hit up the food.
我也许不是为了鸡尾酒虾来的
I may not have come for the shrimp cocktail,
但我要把它们吃光
but I'm gonna eat the shit out of some.
我已经吃了十六只生蚝了
I've already had 16 oysters myself.
再来一个也无妨
17th won't hurt anybody.
不知道你怎么样
I don't know about you,
但我昨晚吃的鸡尾酒虾可能有冒牌货
but not all the cocktails I had last night were shrimp.
谢谢你  唐娜  你不必这么做
Thank you, Donna. You didn't have to.
就像你也不必做这个无偿案
Just like you didn't have to take on this charity.
但我从亚历克斯那了解到
But I got the impression from Alex
关于你  他看到了我看不到的一面
that he saw a side of you that I hadn't,
我觉得我昨晚也看到那一面了
and last night I think I started to see it too.
既然谈到昨晚
Well, as long as we're talking about last night,
我发现有些问题
I may have found something wrong.
你是什么意思
What do you mean?
我想说  慈善机构一般会花费5%的预算
I mean, charities typically spend 5% of their budget
在筹款方面  但根据你朋友
on fundraising, but based on the disclosures
佩吉的披露
I got from your friend, Peggy,
他们过去五年花费了5.3%的预算
they've been at 5.3% for the last five years.
听起来只是多了一点点
Sound like a simple rounding error.
唐娜
Donna.
我对这种事很敏感
I have a nose for this kind of thing,
我觉得佩吉在做见不得人的事
and I think Peggy is up to something shady.
一些习惯于解决问题的人
And the problem with people who fix things
他们的毛病就是看什么都不顺眼
is they can't stop looking for problems to fix.
你觉得我在胡言乱语吗
You think I'm making this up?
我觉得你对那0.3%太执着了
I think you're making .3% into more than it is.
我觉得勾当都在藏细节里
And I think the devil is in the details,
我想告诉你  这个细节有问题
and I am telling you this detail is trouble.
好吧
Okay.
如果你这么肯定  我会找佩吉谈
If you're so sure, I'll talk to Peggy.
或许我该去找她
Maybe I should be the one--
萨曼莎  如果我朋友有事瞒着我
Samantha, if my friend has been lying to me,
我不会视而不见的
I'm not gonna ignore it.
如果你是对的  我会用我的洞察力
I'm gonna turn on my spidey senses,
把事情查清楚
and I'm gonna find out if you're right,
我想让你做的是
and what I want you to do
暂时别管这件事
is not try to fix this in the meantime.
好的  查到了什么告诉我
Okay. Let me know what you find.
哈维  我们需要谈谈
Harvey, we need to talk
因为我们的感情需要维护了
because our relationship needs tending.
你在说什么
Our what needs what?
你没听错  我们的情感关系
You heard me. We're in a relationship,
不是工作上的
and it's not working.
那你把我甩了吧
Then break up with me
我很忙  你去找别人吧
and go out with somebody else 'cause I'm busy.
哈维  我是认真的  我们是搭档
Harvey, I am serious. We're partners.
我们需要经营感情
We need to work on our relationship,
现在这段感情需要维护了
and we need help doing it.
路易  你到底想说什么
Louis, what exactly are you getting at?
利普希茨医生
Dr. Lipschitz.
你的心理医生吗
Your therapist?
-对  他认为...  -我拒绝
- Yeah, and he agreed-- - No.
但是...
But--
路易  我不会陪你一起去见你的心理医生
Louis, there's no way I'm going to a session with your therapist.
事实上是为我们俩治疗
Actually it would be for the both of us.
你是在开玩笑吧
Are you ----ing kidding me?
这是我听过最蠢的事
That's the dumbest thing I've ever heard.
他也认为这是个好主意
Well, he thinks it's a good idea.
那证明你们俩都是蠢货
Which just goes to show that he's an idiot, and so are you.
别把矛头指向我
Don't turn this on me
也别那样评论我的医生
and don't talk about him that way.
发生了什么
What's going on here?
哈维不想和我去做双人治疗
Harvey won't go to couple's counseling with me.
-你说什么  -你看吧
- What? - Exactly.
才不是呢
No, not exactly.
你抢了我的客户  为多米尼克的事生气
Because you took my client; you're upset about Dominic;
你侮辱我  我的医生  还有我的爱人
you insulted me, my therapist, and the woman I love.
如果你为公司利益考虑
And none of that would have happened
而不是图一时之快  这些事都不会发生
if you put the needs of this firm over your afternoon delight.
又来了
And here we go again.
路易  让我和他谈谈好吗
Louis, will you give us a minute?
唐娜  我不想谈这件事
Donna, I don't want to talk about this.
那真糟  根据你
Too bad, because I heard the way
和路易讲话的方式来看
you spoke to Louis before and just now,
一定发生了什么事
and there's clearly stuff going on with you
你处理不了
that you're not dealing with.
可能和你刚刚经历了
Probably has something to do with
马库斯的事有关
what you just went through with Marcus.
和他要离婚一点关系都没有
This has nothing to do with him getting a divorce.
他要什么
He's what?
他打来了电话
He called.
他们不试图和解了
They're not gonna try to work it out.
我不管你去不去看利普希茨医生
Well, I don't care if you go see Lipschitz or someone else,
但你要处理一下自己的情绪
but you need to deal with yourself.
而且不要像以前那样对路易
And stop treating Louis like you used to
因为他已经不是以前那个人了
because he's not that man anymore.
我以为你也变好了的
And I thought you were neither.
-好的  感谢你抽时间  -有什么发现吗
- Okay, thanks for your time. - Anything?
没什么
Nothing.
这已经是我给认识马克·艾肯的人
That was the 15th person I've called
打的第十五个电话了
that knows Marc Aiken, and no one says
所有人都说只是认识
they're anything more than an acquaintance.
这和艾米特告诉我的一样
That tracks with what Emmet told me.
这人没有朋友  没有家庭
The man has no friends, no family,
只有一群受不了他的助手
just a bunch of associates who can barely stand him.
我刚才电话上那头的人说
The guy I just talked to said
他在贵格岭俱乐部预约了开球时间
he's got a standing tee time at Quaker Ridge
就为了在职场上更进一步
for the sole purpose of advancing his career.
我打赌有用
I bet it works.
我爸爸会忍受任何在那里打球的人
My father would tolerate anyone to play there.
-你爸打高尔夫球  -是的  其实我也打
- Your dad's a golfer? - Yeah. I am too, actually.
我第一次知道
Huh, I had no idea.
虽然很喜欢  但我经常打不成
Well, I don't get to play as much as I'd like.
-等等  -怎么了
- Wait a second. - What?
如果他预约了开球时间
If he has a standing tee time,
他就预约了球童
he has a standing caddy.
球童也许不是他能信任的人
And a caddy might not be someone he confides in,
如果他只讨论生意...
but if all he ever talks about is business--
我们得去贵格岭俱乐部
We need to get to Quaker Ridge.
-我们走  -你去
- Let's go. - You go.
我们快没时间了  如果你查到什么
We're running out of time, and if you get something,
我们得准备好向证监会投诉的文件
we're going to need a complaint ready to file with the SCC.
哈维  如果你来是告诉我
Oh, Harvey, if you are here to tell me
我的另一个点子也很蠢的话...
that you think another of my ideas is stupid--
我不是来说这个的  路易
I'm not here to tell you that, Louis.
我是来告诉你我会和你去见利普希茨
I'm here to say I'll go see Lipschitz with you.
你说真的吗  还是这次也是
Do you really mean that, or is this gonna be
我35岁生日你说会请我吃饭
like the time that you said you would take me to dinner
最后没出现的那次
for my 35th birthday ,and you never showed up.
不会像那次
It's not gonna be like that time.
-还是像那次...  -也不是那次
- And what about the time-- - Not that time either.
我会去的  我保证
I'll show up for this. I promise.
这和你那次说的一样
And that's exactly what you said the time--
路易  如果你再说下去
Louis, if you mention one more time,
就会和前几次一样了
it will be like all those times.
那么我想说
Then I want you to know
很感谢你这么做  哈维
that I really appreciate you doing this, Harvey.
为了我们到了之后节约时间
And to save time when we get there,
我得提前告诉你我要坐在沙发左手边
you should know that I sit on the left-hand side of the couch.
好吧
Fine.
也许我不用告诉你
And I probably don't need to tell you this,
你不用自带纸巾
but you don't have to bring your own tissues.
为什么我要自带纸巾
Why would I bring my own tissues?
因为我们要进行深入挖掘  哈维
Because we're gonna be doing some deep work, Harvey.
如果你需要大哭一场
So if you need to have a good cry,
我只想让你知道你很安全
I just want you to know that you're safe,
我不会评判你
and I will not judge you.
待会儿见  路易
See you there, Louis.
等等  你觉得我们现在要抱抱吗
Wait, do you think we should hug now
铺垫情绪  或者一会儿抱...
to set the tone or do it after--
好的  我们一会儿抱  好主意
okay, we'll do it after. Good call.
你在做什么
Hey, what are you doing?
别装作你不知道  唐娜
Don't act like you don't know, Donna.
我被开除了
I've been fired.
什么  我怎么会知道
What? How could I know that?
因为萨曼莎·惠勒打电话
Because it happened after Samantha Wheeler
给我的老板  支票兑付也被暂停了
called my CEO and put a stop payment on that check.
佩吉  你得相信我
Peggy, you have got to believe me.
-这和我一点关系都没有  -有区别吗
- I had nothing to do with that. - What difference does it make?
我的老板责怪我和你们扯上关系
My boss blamed me for getting us involved with you,
-因而开除了我  -完全没道理
- and he fired me. - That's bullshit.
没道理的是我相信了你
What's bullshit is that I trusted you.
而我现在要走人了
And now I'm out on my ass.
你依然可以相信我  佩吉
You can still trust me, Peggy.
我发誓我会处理好这件事
I swear I'm gonna make this right.
你这人有什么问题
What the hell is wrong with you?
-唐娜  -我明确告诉过你在我通知你之前
- Donna-- - I specifically told you not to do anything
不要做任何事  你也说了你不会
until you heard from me, and you said you wouldn't.
我说了我会让你和佩吉谈谈  我做到了
I said I'd let you talk to Peggy, and I did.
就在你向她老板告状
After you called up her boss,
暂停了支票承兑  害她被开除之后
put a stop payment on that check, and got her fired.
我告发她不是为了让她丢工作
I didn't call her boss to get her fired.
我告发是因为我决定相信你的判断
I called because I decided to trust your judgment.
这句话又是什么意思
What is that supposed to mean?
意思是我扪心自问  如果唐娜是对的呢
It means I asked myself, "What if Donna's right?"
如果唯一的问题就是有小商小贩
What if the only thing going on is some vendors
在占慈善机构的便宜呢
taking advantage of a charity.
于是我就找了首席执行官  提出解决方案
So I called up the CEO and offered a solution.
而他却回绝了我的好意
And he said, "No, thanks,
说他们喜欢现在的状态
we like our current situation."
于是你就进行了压力测试
So you ran a stress test
尽管我早告诉你不要这么做
after I told you not to.
我只是打给了一个委托人  提了一个建议
I called a client and made a suggestion.
-别跟我胡扯  -好吧
- Don't bullshit me. - Okay, fine.
那是个测试
It was a test,
但我不能眼看着一位客户捐出五百万
but I'm not gonna let a client donate $5 million
给一个不明就里的人
to anyone without knowing what's what.
我这一招是一石二鸟
So I killed two birds with one stone.
你跟亚历克斯就是这么说的
Which is exactly what you said to Alex
而与我交好本该是
and making good with me was supposed to be
二鸟之一吧
one of those birds.
该死的  唐娜
God damn it, Donna,
你怎么就永远也不信我呢
why don't you ever seem to believe me?
也许是因为你从不对人全盘托出
Maybe because you never give anyone the full story.
你想知道全部吗
You want the full story?
他们在窃取小姑娘们的钱
They are stealing money from little girls.
或许这对你来说不重要
Maybe that doesn't matter to you,
但对我来说这重要之极
but it sure as hell as matters to me.
我看重什么你根本不懂
You don't know what matters to me.
要处理这事你有的是办法
And there are about 500 different ways you could have handled this,
你却选了会让我失去朋友的一种
and you picked the one that cost me my friend.
所以在我看来
So as far as I'm concerned,
我对你的看法一直是对的
I was right about you all along.
既然我们已经介绍过了
Now that we've made our introductions,
我想请哈维先讲讲
I'd like to start with Harvey
在他看来
describing what he thinks
路易是如何看待对当前状况的
Louis' perspective is on the situation.
我不太喜欢这样
I don't feel comfortable--
请吧  就说说你想到的第一个念头
Please, just say the first thoughts that come to mind.
关于路易的想法吗
About how Louis thinks?
我想想
Huh. Let's see...
猫  芭蕾  哈维·斯佩克特  这种
Cats, ballet, Harvey Specter. Something like that.
我听起来可不是这样的
That is not what I sound like.
好吧  路易
All right, Louis.
你知道在我听来你是怎么想的吗
You wanna know what you sound like to me?
自打第一天起  你就在嫉妒我
"I've been jealous of you since day one.
杰西卡总是最看重我  其他人也最喜欢我
"You were always Jessica's favorite and everyone else's.
我不费吹灰之力就得到了你想要的一切
"You got everything I wanted without ever trying.
事实上  你一直在努力要小孩
"In fact, I'm trying to have a baby
因为你觉得这能让你不想我的事
"Because, I-I-I think it will take my mind off you
但你内心里清楚地知道这根本不管用
even though I know deep inside it won't."
快让他闭嘴
Tell him to stop.
他说的都是真情实感  路易
He's being honest about his feelings, Louis.
那整件事谁对谁错
What about your feelings about
你又是怎么想的呢
who's fault this whole thing was?
-路易  -什么
- Louis. - What?
我早就该知道  你就是想
I should have known you just wanted
拽我来这儿
to get me in here
让他告诉我这全是我的错
to have him tell me this is my fault.
本来就是你的错
It is your fault.
路易  我们来这儿不是追究对错的
Louis, we are not here to discuss fault.
那我们来这儿到底是干什么的
Well, then why the hell are we here?
他抢了我的客户  还不想还回来
Because he took my client; he won't give her back;
而且他刚刚拿我要孩子的事说事
and he needs to apologize about what he just said
他得为此向我道歉
about me having a baby.
我不会为任何事道歉
I am not apologizing about anything.
是你要我来的
You wanted me to come here.
你说这里很安全
You said this was a safe place.
而现在你没法接受
And now you can't handle
我对你想要小孩这件事的想法
what I think about you trying to have a baby.
不  你不能把这说成是我的错
Oh, no, you don't get to make this my fault.
因为每次你都说是我的错
Because it's always my fault,
但我想这次我们可以来这里
but I thought this time we could come here
好让你告诉他  这全是他的错
so you could tell him that it's his fault,
但要是你只会嘲笑我
but if all you're gonna do is mock me
而你只会一味偏袒他
and all you're gonna do is coddle him,
那你就留着琼·沃尔吧
well, then you can keep Joan Walsh;
你可以去死了
you can go to hell;
本次会议到此结束
and this whole session is over.
这真是浪费时间
Well, this was a waste of time.
或许吧  但还是值得的
Maybe so, but for what it's worth...
我觉得有些事你可以改善一下
I think you have some things you could work on.
如果路易可以接受的话
And provided Louis was okay...
我随时欢迎你来找我
I'd be happy to talk with you any time.
亚历克斯
Alex,
我需要你撤回停止支付的指示
I need you to reverse that stop payment.
什么
What?
我需要你给那个客户打电话
I said I need you to call up that client
让他们把捐赠资金就位
and tell them to let that donation go through.
我不会那么做的
Well, I'm not gonna do that
因为萨曼莎把事情告诉我了
because Samantha told me what's going on.
萨曼莎根本不清楚情况
Samantha doesn't know what's going on,
你不该把她牵扯进来
and you were wrong to involve her.
-你是来找我追究责任的  -不  我来
- So this is about me. - No, this is about the fact
是为了我朋友刚被开除的事
that my friend just got fired.
我很遗憾  唐娜  但我帮不了你
Well, I'm sorry to hear that, Donna, but I can't help you.
不用帮我  帮帮那家慈善机构
Then don't help me. Help the charity.
你正在从急需资助的人手里夺走资金
Because you're taking money away from people who need it.
唐娜  要是我照你说的办
Donna, if I do what you're asking
那就等于告诉客户他们不能信任我的建议
I might as well tell my clients they can't trust my advice.
我给你的建议就是清醒一点
And my advice to you is get your head on straight.
你是说我没把事情看清楚
You're saying I'm not seeing this clearly.
我是说萨曼莎了解灰色地带
I'm saying Samantha specializes in shady shit.
要是她怀疑什么事情
So if she suspects something's up
尽管你可能不相信  但我信
you might not believe it, but I do.
我不会再给那家慈善机构开支票了
And I'm not cutting that charity another check.
完事了
Almost done?
-抱歉  卡特里娜  -没事
- Sorry, Katrina. - That's okay.
我感觉你在想事情
I take it you were thinking about something.
说实话
To tell you the truth,
我确实是来这里思考的
I actually came in here to think.
但我占用它够久了
But I've hogged this thing long enough.
归你了
It's all yours.
趁你还在
As long as you're here,
你介意我问你个问题吗
do you mind if I ask you a question?
当然不  什么问题
Of course, what is it?
路易说要是我赢了这案子
Louis said if I win this case
我就能升任高级合伙人  但
I'll finally make senior partner, but--
他以前就这么说过
He's said that before,
你想知道他这次是不是说真的
and you wanna know if this time it's true?
对
I do.
答案是  是真的
Then the answer is yes.
没错
It is.
谢谢  唐娜
Thanks, Donna.
趁你还在
As long as you're here,
你介意我问你点事吗
do you mind if I ask you something?
你和布莱恩是怎么回事
What's going on with you and Brian?
什么
What?
你们昨晚一起工作时
I noticed when the two of you were working together last night
我留意到你们似乎  变亲近了
you seemed to have gotten... closer.
的确  我们成了朋友
We have. We've become friends.
你们俩好像比朋友更亲近点
Looks like you might be becoming more than that.
唐娜  他结婚了
Donna, he's married.
他有个儿子  我决不会那么做的
He has a son. I would never do it.
我知道  但我也知道
I know, but I also know that the heart
并不是大脑说决不能如何
doesn't always listen to what the brain says
心就会照办的
it would never do.
你用不着担心
Well, you don't need to worry
我对布莱恩除了友情没有别的
because I don't feel anything for Brian except friendship.
那祝你这案件顺利
Then good luck with the case.
复印机归你了
Copier's all yours.
你想干什么  斯坦
So what do you want do now, Stan?
跟我说毒蛇德雷克也是我的错吗
Tell me Drake the Snake was my fault too?
路易  我知道我们的疗程不太顺利
Louis, I know our session didn't go as planned,
但我觉得并非希望全无
but I do think there is still some hope.
所以
So...
我希望你能乐意让我和哈维一对一咨询
I'd like your blessing to begin seeing Harvey one on one.
你开什么玩笑  你又站他那边了
Are you fucking kidding me? You're choosing his side again?
我不是站他那边  路易
I am not choosing his side, Louis.
我想帮你们俩
I am trying to help both of you.
你才不是  在我和哈维之间做选择的话
No, you're not, because anyone who has a choice
人人都会选他
between Harvey and me always chooses him.
你明知我最害怕这个
You know it's my biggest fear, and you made it out
你还把一切都弄得像是我的错
like it was all my fault.
我没有
No, I didn't,
我坚持我的结论
and I stand by my assessment.
现状中的一些问题
There are aspects of this situation
是哈维造成的
that are of Harvey's making.
那你为什么不跟他说  斯坦
Well, then why didn't you say that to him, Stan?
路易  因为人受伤时
Because, Louis, when someone is hurting,
不该被落井下石
you don't throw stones at them.
你说哈维受伤是什么意思
What do you mean Harvey's hurting?
人们痛苦时会乱发脾气
I mean, people lash out when they are in pain.
他朝你发脾气  要是你在意
He lashed out at you, and if you care about
你和他的关系  就让我做我的工作
your relationship with him, you will let me do my job.
如果我不在乎我和他的关系
What if I don't care about my relationship with him,
我宁愿把你留着我自己用呢
and I'd rather keep you to myself?
路易  我知道你有多关心哈维
Louis, I know how much you care
甚至在他伤害你的时候
about Harvey even when he hurts you.
这是我一直钦佩你的事情
That is something I have always admired about you,
我不认为你该轻视这件事
and I do not think you should take it lightly.
他可以见你
All right, he can see you,
但是他不会得到我的祝福
but he doesn't have my blessing.
卡特里娜  我和艾肯的球童谈了
Katrina, I talked to Aiken's caddy.
我使了所有能用的伎俩  他还是排斥我
I tried every trick in the book. He froze me out.
我们不只是被排斥  布莱恩
We didn't just get frozen out, Brian.
他们还以诽谤马克递交了反诉
They slapped us with a countersuit for slandering Marc.
我们把情况弄的更糟糕了
We just made it 1,000 times worse.
-也许我们还可以...  -简直难以置信
- Shit. Look, maybe we can still - I can't ----ing believe it!
卡特里娜  这只是个案子
Katrina, it's just a case.
不  这不仅仅是个案子
No, it's not just a case.
-这关系到我的高级合伙人位子  -什么
- It's my senior partnership. - What?
但我以为路易斯说...
But I thought Louis said...
我知道他说了什么  但出了岔子
I know what he said, but there was a hitch.
这件案子关乎我能否升职
This was the case to put me over the top.
你为什么不告诉我
Why didn't you tell me?
因为这是我自己的事业我的责任
Because it's my career and my responsibility.
卡特里娜  我不只是本案的
Katrina, I'm not just the other name
合作律师  我是你的朋友
on this lawsuit, I'm your friend.
如果高级合伙人位子对你来说
If senior partner's on the line
已是生死一线  那么对我也是
for you, it is for me too.
现在  我们可以继续
Now, we can still--
不只是诉讼里的一个名字
Not just a name on a lawsuit.
-没凑  -什么
- That's it. - What's it?
诉讼记录上的律师
The attorney of record on this suit isn't
和陪艾肯录证词的律师不是同一个
the same attorney Aiken took the deposition with.
他在案子中间换了律师
He changed lawyers in the middle of the case.
你想说什么
What are you getting at?
他们昨晚撤回了证词
They sent back the deposition last night
那个新的律师签的名  布莱恩  让他
and the new guy signed it. Brian, it's one thing
处理诽谤案是一件事
to have him handle the slander case,
但是签署一份证词又是另一回事了
but to sign off on a deposition.
第一个律师知道艾肯在撒谎
The first guy knew Aiken was lying,
他不肯签署证词  他不愿教唆做伪证
and he wouldn't sign it. He wouldn't suborn perjury.
卡特里娜  我们抓住他了
Katrina, we got him.
我知道
I know.
我们要去拿那盘带子
We're going to get that tape.
我们看看在艾肯说自己无罪时
We're gonna look at his reaction
他是什么反应
when Aiken says he's innocent.
我们要一起查出他们的整个记录
We're gonna find out their entire history together.
我不管要不要花一整晚
I don't care if it takes all night.
太棒了  我要去点那个玛莎拉
This is fantastic. I'm gonna go order that masala;
你肯定要弄得满脸都是
you're gonna get it all over your face;
这次我连告诉都不告诉你
I'm not even gonna tell you about it this time.
你最好告诉我
You better tell me about it
而且你最好再点个印度烤饼
just like you better get extra naan.
三倍极致美味的印度烤饼
Triple supreme naan it is.
我去下单了  给我老婆快速地打个电话
I'm just gonna go order it, call my wife real quick
告诉她不用等我了  然后你和我
to tell her not to wait up, and then you and I--
等等  停下  不要
Wait, stop. No.
不要什么
No what?
你今晚不用留在这
You're not staying tonight.
我可以自己处理  我也打算这么做
I can handle this myself, and I'm going to.
卡特里娜  怎么了  我做错什么了吗
Katrina, what's going on? Did I do something wrong?
没有  布莱恩
You've done nothing wrong, Brian.
但是你有妻子有孩子
But you've got a wife and a baby,
我不能继续让你疏远家人了
and I'm not going to keep you from them anymore than I already have.
卡特里娜  我说了你的合伙人位置
Katrina, I told you if your partnership's
岌岌可危  就相当于我的位置岌岌可危
on the line, my partnership's on the line.
我知道  但我可以的
I know, but I got this.
回家
Go home.
介意我进来吗
You mind if I come in?
不介意
No.
我正要去见你
I was just about to come see you.
在你告诉我原因之前
Well, before you tell me why,
我想先道歉
I'd like to apologize.
你要道歉吗
You would?
是的
Yes.
我意识到我在这件事上投入了个人感情
I realized I'm too close to this.
我斥责了你  而没有认真听你的话  抱歉
And instead of hearing you, I lashed out, and I'm sorry.
你意识到了
You realized?
我去见了亚历克斯
I went to see Alex.
有趣
Well, that's funny,
因为我也想道歉
because I wanted to apologize too.
你想道歉
You wanted to apologize?
唐娜  我跟你说过不会轻举妄动
Donna, I told you I wouldn't take action,
我也不应该  但我没忍住
and I shouldn't have. But I couldn't help myself.
因为我关心这些孩子
because I care about the kids this charity
慈善机构本该照顾好他们
is supposed to serve.
但你不会知道  因为如你所说
But you wouldn't know that, because like you said,
我从不把事情和盘托出
I never tell anyone the full story.
我不这么做的原因是
And the reason I never tell the full story
我不信任
is because I just don't trust--
其他人
people.
差不多吧  对
Pretty much. Yeah.
亚历克斯跟我聊过后又找你聊了  对吧
Alex talked to you after he talked to me, didn't he?
对
He did.
这个人太可怕已经不能忽视了
We might have to do something about that guy.
没错
We might.
但首先我们得解决这个问题
But not before we do something about this situation.
他们欺诈孩子们
Because I'm not gonna let them get away
我要让他们付出代价
with scamming children.
这我同意
I'm with you on that.
那我问你
Then let me ask.
你能读懂人心
You read people.
你真的确定佩吉没有参与其中
Are you absolutely sure Peggy wasn't in on this,
因为就算她参与了  他们也可能解雇她
because they could have fired her even if she was.
我百分之百确定
I am 100% sure.
那我知道怎么做了
Then I know what to do.
我很开心你来找了我
I'm glad you decided to come in.
介不介意我问问
You mind if I ask
你怎么让路易同意让我来见你的
how you got Louis to agree to let me see you?
不介意  但我更想问你
I don't, but I would prefer to ask:
路易来时说到  你正失去
when Louis came in and said you were losing
麦肯诺汽车公司这个客户  你感觉如何
this McKernon Motors, how did you feel?
直奔主题  是吗
You want to just jump right in, huh?
是的
Yes, I do.
你觉得我有何感觉  我不喜欢
Well, how do you think I felt? I didn't like it.
因为你失去了自己最老的客户
Because you were losing your oldest client?
因为路易告诉我我什么也不能做
Because Louis told me there was nothing I could do about it.
之后唐娜过来说琼来了
And then Donna came in and said Joan was there,
路易也无法把她的事办妥
and Louis couldn't even take care of her.
-这让你恼怒  -是愤怒
- And it irritated you? - It infuriated me.
-为什么  -因为他跟我说
- Why? - Because he told me
我得不到自己想要的
that I couldn't have what I wanted
然后他将一己私利
and then he put his own selfish interests
置于整个律所之上
above the firm's.
请原谅 哈维
Forgive me, Harvey,
但那不是一直以来路易对你的顾虑吗
but isn't that Louis' historical concern about you?
这不一样
This is different.
我觉得不同的原因是
I think perhaps it is different
现在是他这么对你了
because he is the one doing it to you,
更重要的是
and more importantly,
他的一己私利是什么
what those selfish interests are.
你想说什么
What are you getting at?
你们俩来的时候
When you two were here,
你花了很多时间抱怨路易生孩子的事
you spent quite a lot of time on Louis having a baby.
所以呢
So?
你想过要孩子吗  或者组建家庭
So would you ever want to have a baby? Or a family?
我有一个家  如果你想说
I have a family, and if you're gonna say
这跟我弟弟的离婚有关
this has something to do with my brother's divorce--
我根本不知道此事
I didn't even know your brother was getting a divorce.
他要离婚了
Well, he is.
-那一定很痛苦  -当然了
- That must be painful. - Of course it's painful.
我的家庭破碎了  与此同时
My family's falling apart, and at the same time
路易的家庭发展壮大
I'm getting it rubbed in my face
还在我面前炫耀
that Louis' family is growing.
对不起  哈维  但是
Forgive me, Harvey, but...
路易并未在你面前炫耀
Louis did not rub anything in your face.
对  他没有
No, he didn't.
但这种感觉的由来
But perhaps it feels that way
可能是因为这是第一次
because for the first time,
路易生命中有的东西  你没有
Louis has something in his life that you do not.
老天  你在说我嫉妒路易
Jesus Christ, you're saying I'm envious of Louis.
嫉妒又如何
And what if you were?
我想问那我应该怎么办
I'd ask what in God's name am I supposed to do with that?
你有没有想过跟他说说这事
Does is it occur to you to share that with him?
没  就算我想  他也很生我的气
No, even if I wanted to, he's pissed off at me.
他会立刻原谅你的
He would forgive you in a moment.
就算他会  我很怕
And even if he did, I'm afraid to--
怕什么  哈维
To what, Harvey?
路易会在生活中
Louis makes space for the people
为爱的人腾出空间
in his life whom he loves.
他会为希拉和宝宝腾出空间
He makes space for people like Sheila and a baby,
-但是  -但是什么
- but-- - But what?
一旦他有了宝宝
But once he has that baby,
他的生活中可能没有我的位置了
he might not make space for me.
你为什么会觉得
Where would you get a notion like that,
路易不会再为你腾时间
that Louis wouldn't have time for you?
因为人们总是离开我  所有人都是
Because they leave. Everyone leaves:
迈克  瑞秋  杰西卡  我嫂子
Mike, Rachel, Jessica, my sister-in-law.
所有人
Everyone.
我可以告诉你
Well, I can tell you
如果你还继续这样待路易
if you keep treating Louis like this,
你自己会把他逼走
you may cause him to leave yourself.
詹姆斯·达文波特  我是唐娜·保尔森
James Davenport? I'm Donna Paulsen,
这是我同事萨曼莎·惠勒
and this is my colleague Samantha Wheeler.
那个从我们这里
The same Samantha Wheeler
抢走五百万捐款的萨曼莎·惠勒吗
that had a $5 million donation yanked from us?
那个为你提供了下个活动场地
The Samantha Wheeler who offered you a venue
且给你节省了一大笔钱的萨曼莎·惠勒
for your next event for a fraction of the one
但你拒绝了
you've been using, and you said no.
意味着你多付钱给现在的场地供应商
Which means you cut a deal with your current venue
并从他们那里拿回扣
where you overpay and they kick back a percentage to you.
准确来说  是你年预算的百分之三
Specifically, .3% of your annual budget.
-滚出去  -我不这么认为  詹姆斯
- Get out of my office. - I don't think so, James.
虽然我们没时间找证据
Because we may not have had time to find proof,
但记者有时间
but a reporter will.
尤其当被告知你开除了一位无辜女士
Especially after we tell them that you fired an innocent woman
就因为潜在捐赠者问了账本相关的问题时
just because a potential donor asked a few questions about your books.
听你这么说
When you put it that way,
感觉他是在掩盖自己的罪行
it sounds like he did all this to cover his guilty ass.
也许我们应该把这个告诉《华尔街日报》
Maybe we should give that to the "Journal."
肯定是篇好文章
That's a nice turn of phrase.
谢谢  唐娜
Thank you, Donna.
你们想要什么
What do you want?
我们想要你辞职
We want you to step down
并让佩吉·戴维斯接任
and name Peggy Davis as your replacement.
-别开玩笑了  -你不会想知道
- You can't be serious. - You don't want to find out
我们有多认真  詹姆斯
how serious we are, James.
因为你正面对着两位怒火中烧还恰好知道
Because you're looking at two pissed-off women
你的肮脏勾当和如何证明的女人
who know exactly what you did and how to prove it.
今晚你们会收到我的辞呈
You'll have my resignation by tonight.
很好  别这么看着我
Good. And don't look at me like that.
如果不是因为我想保住你的慈善机构
If it wouldn't mean your charity would go out of business,
你就要蹲五年大牢了
you'd be spending the next five years in prison.
结果如何
How'd it go?
我们赢了
We won.
听着  关于昨晚
Listen, about last night--
布莱恩  我不是有意要...
Brian, I didn't mean to come off like--
你什么也没做
You didn't come off like anything.
我只想谢谢你没有强留我
I just wanted to thank you for not making me stay.
-但我以为你想  -我知道  我想帮忙
- But I thought you wanted-- - I know. I wanted to help.
不过朱莉和我度过了一个美好的夜晚
But Julie and I, we had a great time.
奥斯汀整晚都在睡觉  我们竟然
Austin slept through the night, and we actually stayed up
看完了《早餐俱乐部》
and watched "The Breakfast Club."
那是什么
What's that?
我和朱莉最爱的电影
Uh, just Julie and my favorite movie of all time.
-我从没听说过  -天哪
- I've never heard of it. - Oh, my God.
你从没听说过
You've never even heard of it?
你必须得看看  下次我给你带碟
You have to see it. I'm bringing you a copy.
布莱恩  你没必要这么做
Brian, you don't have to do that.
我知道  但我们是朋友
I know I don't, but that's what friends do.
朋友
Friends.
是啊  朋友
Yeah, friends.
我们说好了的  不是吗
That's what we said, right?
对  没错
Yes, it is.
谢谢  我很想看看这电影
And thanks, I would love to see it sometime.
你想去吃午饭吗
Hey, you want to get some lunch?
好啊
Sure.
这也是朋友间会做的事情  对吗
I mean, that's also what friends do, right?
我是你第一个朋友吗
Am I your first friend?
当然不是
You know you're not.
来吧  我们走
Come on, let's go.
你拿到他的辞呈了吗
You get that letter of resignation?
就在这里
Right here.
佩吉的任命书马上就到
And Peggy's job offer is on its way.
-听着  唐娜  -听着  萨曼莎
- Look, Donna-- - Listen, Samantha--
这次我先说
Let me go first this time.
我在思考我以前一直不信任别人
I was thinking about how I don't trust people.
然后觉得自己应该改变一下
And I thought maybe I should start.
但我又转念一想
And then I thought,
也许我该先告诉你
maybe I should start by telling you
为什么我对那个慈善机构如此上心
why I cared so much about this charity in the first place.
喝红葡萄酒讲这个故事还是马蒂尼
Is this a rosé story or a martini story?
威士忌
Whiskey.
今晚如何
How about tonight?
很棒
That would be nice.
半小时后大厅见
Meet you in the lobby in half an hour?
没问题
You got it.
到时候见
See you down there.
真高兴是在这里找到了你
I'm glad I caught you in here of all places.
为什么
Why's that?
因为我们在这里共度了很多时光
Because we have a lot of history here.
我感觉这里是一个
And it seems like the right place
适合和好的地方
for me to make things right.
你肯定是去见了斯坦
You must have gone to see Stan.
没错  谢谢
I did. Thank you for that.
来和好  还感谢我
Make things right. Thanking me.
发生了什么
What went on in there?
其他的不说
Among other things,
他帮助我意识到了我其实
he helped me realize I care about you;
我很看重你
I value you;
我当时是害怕
and I was afraid of--
失去我
Losing me?
所以你才推开我
Which is why you pushed me away.
天哪
Oh, my God.
你做了我会做的事
You pulled a Litt.
哈维  你变成我了
Harvey, you became me.
路易  我觉得还没到那个地步
Louis, I wouldn't go that far.
绝对有  而且你就是有
Oh, no, you would. And you did.
我们简直是异母兄弟
We are brothers from another mother.
如果你现在不立刻重复这句话
And if you don't say that right now,
我就告诉所有人你害怕失去我
I'm gonna tell everyone you're afraid of losing me.
-路易  -马上
- Louis. - Right now.
我第一个告诉保罗·波特
Starting with Paul Porter.
我们简直是异母兄弟
We're brothers from another mother.
抱歉  没听到  能再说一遍吗
I'm sorry, I couldn't-- could you repeat that?
-不行  路易  -为什么
- No, Louis, I couldn't. - Why not?
因为我知道你打算
Because I know you're about to record it
-录下来  -那又怎么样
- on your Dictaphone. - And what if I am?
因为如果你不重复
Because if you don't say it again,
我就告诉所有人你害怕失去我
I'm gonna tell everyone you're afraid of losing me.
你再说一遍这话
And if you say that one more time,
我们友谊就翻船  而且我再也不理你了
our friendship's over, and I'm never looking back.
因为我是临时心软了一下
Because I suffered a momentary weakness,
但是别忘了这个情景里谁是谁
but let's not forget who's who in this situation.
我不再提了
I'll never mention it again.
把手放在我能看到的地方
Now, put your hands where I can see 'em.
-为什么  -照办
- Why? - Just do it.
你这是干什么
What the hell did you do that for?
因为我们今晚要一起出去
Because, you and me are going out tonight.
我要说很多夸你的话
I'm gonna say a lot of nice things to you,
这些话我绝对不要录下来
and there isn't gonna be any record of it.
可以接受
I can live with that.
等等
Wait a minute.
你花了多久时间才决定去找斯坦的
How long did it take for you to come to that with Stan?
-25分钟吧  怎么了  -难以置信
- About 25 minutes, why? - I don't believe it.
看心理医生的事上你都比我强
You're even better at therapy than I am.
也许  但相信我
Maybe I am. But trust me.
斯坦认为你比我强  一直如此
Stan likes you better than me, and he always will.
-你真这么想吗  -不  路易  骗你的
- You really think so? - No, Louis, I don't.
等等
Wait a minute.
这是不是意味着琼可以回来了
Does this mean I get to have Joan back?
没错
You sure can.
而且第一件你要去做的
And your first order of business
就是告诉她我们递交了
is gonna be telling her we filed suit
针对一个16岁孩子的诉讼
against a 16-year-old
会让她颜面扫地
that's gonna make her look like shit.
什么  你真这么做了吗
What? You really did that?
我能说什么呢  路易
What can I tell you, Louis?
害怕失去你会让人干傻事
The fear of losing you makes a man do crazy things.
这样的话  等希拉和我有了孩子
Well, in that case, after Sheila and I are pregnant,
我们一起去做泥浴吧
do you want to go mudding?
-不  路易  我拒绝  -那...
- No, Louis, I don't. - Well, h--